这有Reddies 伙计
Got that reddies, son.
买一送一 买一送一
Two for one, two for one.
卖Rasheed和Beno
I got that Rasheed and Beno.
Rasheed和Beno
Rasheed and Beno.
给他小弟弟敷点冰
Put some ice on his nuts.
绝对有效 能把他弄醒
Tried and true, that shit always bring a nigga back.
在这上哪找冰去
Where we gonna get ice from down here?
- 把他扶到Bon Secours去 - Rasheed和Beno Rasheed和Beno...
- Walk him up to Bon Secours. - Rasheed and Beno. Rasheed and Beno...
呃... 能给我一份八球吗 (八分之一盎司可卡因)
Um... Can you give me an eight-ball?
一份八球 嗯?
A eight-ball, huh?
今天过得怎样
So, how you doing today?
无意冒犯 不过给我八球就好行吗
No offense, but can you just get the eight-ball?
好 好 不过想闲聊一下
All right, all right. Just being social.
这儿有货
Got it right here, yo.
谢谢
Thank you.
听说Mack Man珠宝店昨晚被洗劫了吗
You hear Mack Man jewelers got took off last night?
那排屋里都是 那边
Got all this shit in the row house. Down yonder.
要尽快出手
Like a must-move situation.
15美元一件
Fifteen on the dollar.
想要上佳的钻石的话
Y'all want some slamming ice,
进去跟我伙计说Rafik让你来的
Go inside and tell my man Rafik sent you.
火机 烟斗 火柴
Lighters, pipes, matches.
烟斗 火机
Pipes, lighters.
要什么有什么 来买啊 烟斗
You need them, I got them. Right here, pipes.
Reddies
Reddies.
买一送一 买一送一
Two for one, two for one.
问我有没有上膛啊 贱货
Ask me if it's loaded, bitch.
Reddies 伙计 买一送一
Reddies, son, two for one.
有什么情况
Anything up?
有一批货进来
Just a good package.
三个吸毒过量的
Three OD's.
最后一个看上去情况不太秒 救护车来了
Last one didn't look too good before the ambo came, neither.
该死
Oh, shit.
里面还有很多 Carv
There's more inside, Carv.
该死 想找警察时警察都死哪去了
Goddamn! Can't you ever get a fucking police around here when you need one?
火线重案组 第三季 第8集
the.wire.s03e08
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
"爬 走 最后才是跑"      -Clay Davis
好吧 那个一次性手机?
Okay, on that burner?
我给Trac打电话
I called Trac,
把序列号给他们
Gave them the serial number.
Trac公司说他们卖给Northland了
Trac Corporation told me that they sent it to Northland
一个采购公司
A purchasing corporation.
Northland说他们把它发到了 在Hagerstown的配销中心
Northland tells me they sent it to their distribution center in Hagerstown.
Hagerstown说他们把货发到了 Buddy's Mondo超市...
Hagerstown tells me they sent it to Buddy's Mondo Mart...
地址Propane路1440号
At 1440 Propane Road,
Falls Church 弗吉尼亚
Falls Church, Virginia.
就是从那卖出的
That's where it went out into the street.
- 干嘛 - Buddy是把他们放在收银机的左边还是右边卖的
- What? - Did Buddy have them on display to the left or the right of the cash register?
我怎么会知道
How would I know that?
好吧
All right.
至于那电话的快速拨号...
As for the numbers in the phone's speed dial...
其中有一个本地号码
We got one local number.
是Bodie奶奶家的...
One number that tracks to Bodie's grandmother's house...
在西巴尔的摩街...
On West Baltimore Street...
另外六个号码都对应Trac的一次性手机
And six other numbers that are all assigned to Trac disposable cell phones.
都是城外买的
And those phones were all purchased outside the city.
一个在Catonsville
One each in Catonsville,
Laurel Bethesda...
Laurel, Bethesda...
还有弗吉尼亚的店里...
And stores in Virginia...
Springfield
At Springfield,
Dumfries和Lakeside
Dumfries and Lakeside.
都是沿l95公路
Everything's along l-95,
从这差不多到Richmond了
From here to almost Richmond.
他们每两周开200里 十分小心
They're driving 200 miles every couple of weeks out of sheer caution.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
什么漂亮
What is?
这种章法
The discipline of it.
你有想过这辈子还能看见...
In your life, did you think you would ever again
Mount和Fayette街角这么清静吗
See Mount and Fayette like this?
耳边不再是毒贩的兜售声 哥们
Those ain't touts you're hearing, brother.
而是鸟叫声
Those are birds chirping.
怎么办到的
How?
我带你去看
I'll show you.
你们说不许望风 不许有打手 不许争执
You said no whistles, no muscle, no flexing.
这些该是你们负责 伙计
You supposed to be all over that shit, man.
你们甚至还说这里会成为伊甸园
You even said it's supposed to be like the Valley of Eden.
服务民众 保卫民众 混球
To serve and protect, Motherfuckers.
- 就当是理想的不公平吧 - 我要报案
- Call it poetic injustice. - I want to file a report.
- 说什么 - 你听到了
- Say what? - You heard me.
你要跟我们抱怨
You want to make a complaint to us
你卖毒品被人打劫?
That you were selling drugs and someone took your money?
靠 没错
Fuck, yes.
- 这儿 - Fredericksburg?
- Here. - Fredericksburg?
他们这么大老远地跑去买手机?
They're going all that way to buy cell phones?
这一个 这两个 没有大批量购入
One here, two there. No wholesale purchases.
他们大约两周扔一次手机...
They've been dumping phones every two weeks or so...
还在担心被窃听
And still they're worried about catching a wiretap.
虽然是过分担心了 但也不代表没人想逮住你 对吧
Just 'cause you're paranoid doesn't mean someone's not out to get you, right?
不过如果能知道是谁买了手机倒也不赖
Lt'd be nice to know who's buying all those cell phones, though.
我开车
I'll drive.
嘿 嘿 嘿 要货吗 老头
Yo, yo, yo, yo. You up, old man?
不过他们言之在理
They do have a point though, right?
我是说 我们让他们不带武器来这...
I mean, we tell them to come down here without the guns...
却疏于提供保护
And then we fall down on providing protection.
那些抢劫团伙
It's like the stickup crews have these hoppers
让毒贩觉得自己像活在羊圈里
Feeling like they live in a lamb pen.
他们要再见到枪
They see one more gun,
我保证和平就要分崩离析了
Gandhi-world falls apart, this I guarantee.
那你怎么处理的
So what are you doing about it?
我让几个混混跟Herc回分局了
I sent a few of the vics over to the district with Herc.
让他们做个面部成像 但你也知道会不了了之
Let them play with an Ident-A-Kit, but you know how that goes.
我能实话实说吗
Can I be honest?
威胁羊圈的可不只是狼
It's not just the wolves circling the corral.
这里面有五六十个小鬼
We got 50, 60 kids on the inside
自打出来混就打架 乱窜
Been fight or flight since they popped out the chute
现在他们却无所事事
And right now they're just thumb-up-their-ass hanging.
所有这些之前逃腿的
All these ex-runners,
望风的
Ex-lookouts.
这些人跟外面那些抢劫犯一样让我担心
That shit worries me as much as any carnivores out there.
如果你想中和一些威胁
If you want to neutralize a threat,
给他们点活干
Give it a job.
比如?
As?
义务警察
Auxiliary cops.
盯着那些抢劫犯
Keep an eye out for the predators.
反正他们现在也是拿钱不干事
You got the dealers paying them to do nothing no-how anyway.
- 一举两得 - 是啊
- Kill two birds and all that. - Right.
给他们些自行车 也许还有警用无线电
Throw them some bikes, maybe police radios.
是个好主意
We could do that.
我一直...
I was being...
你认真的?
You're serious?
你他妈在搞什么
What in God's name did you do here?
大杀器 来买大杀器
WMD. Got that WMD.
嘿 你好
Hey, how you doing?
我们来找个人
We're looking for a guy who came in here,
10或11天前在这用现金买了一次性电话
Ten or eleven days ago dropped cash on a couple of disposable phones?
10或11天前?
Ten or eleven days ago?
对 很可能是黑人
Yeah. Black, most likely.
那范围还真是缩小多了哈
That really narrows it down.
我们看看你们的监控录像怎么样
How about we just check on some of your security tapes?
10天前的?
From ten days ago?
除非有突发事件
Unless there's an incident,
我们每周循环使用录像带
We reuse those videotapes every week.
每周?
Every week?
这是Mondo超市的规定
It's Mondo Mart policy.
进展顺利啊
That went well.
- 喂 - Briana Barksdale给你打过电话
- Yeah? - Briana Barksdale called for you.
- 谁 - D'Angelo Barksdale的母亲
- Who? - D'Angelo Barksdale's mother.
记下她号码了吗
You get her number?
有笔吗
You got a pen?
410-718-9433 记下了?
410-718-9433. Got it?
- 好了 - 你会打给她吗 - 不知道
- All right. - You gonna call her? - I don't know.
你看着办吧
It's all yours.
谢谢 Jay
Thanks, Jay.
嘿 来看看
Hey, check it out.
Mondo超市 Mondo超市 Mondo超市 Mondo超市
Mondo Mart, Mondo Mart, Mondo Mart, Mondo Mart.
搞笑了
We're fucked.
要到这儿
Until we get here.
BaBa Jani食品超市 Dumfries 弗吉尼亚
BaBa Jani Food Mart, Dumfries, Virginia.
我们要为这家伙会被人记住或拍下 这一微弱的希望跑上100里?
We're gonna go 100 miles on the off-chance this guy has a memory or a camera?
你真想提早回去 让Lester Freamon失望?
Do you really wanna go home early and disappoint Lester Freamon?
谁打来的
Who was that who rang?
猜猜谁因为D'Angelo Barksdale的事 打到凶杀科找我?
Guess who's calling Homicide looking for me on D'Angelo Barksdale?
- 他妈妈 - 是吗
- His mama. - Yeah?
靠 我都忘了我想搞那事了
Shit, I forgot I even tried to press that thing.
现在她不停打过来问
Now she's calling up asking questions.
浪费她自己的时间 好像那时间是我的
Waste of her time as it was mine.
就像这次旅途一样
Kind of like this road trip.
他看着很自然
He do look natural.
混球Marlo
That motherfucker Marlo.
我们一定要找他算账
We gonna have to get deep on this nigga.
我是说 好像什么都没改变
I mean, it feels like ain't shit changed
除了我钱包越来越轻
Except for a growing lightness in my wallet.
我的房屋维护局那帮混球的批准书呢
Where's my letter of approval, man, from the Preservation motherfuckers?
- 我的路权协议 签字保证呢? - 稍安勿躁 稍安勿躁
- My right-of-way agreement, my sign-offs? - Hold on, hold on, hold on.
很快就会有消息的
Everything's right around the corner.
我们已经找好了明天的管道和电路检察员
We got both the plumbing and the electrical inspectors on for tomorrow
周二就是消防署的人 会搞定的 String
Tuesday, the fire department's coming out and that should do it, String,
一切都会上轨道
You'll be on your way.
顺便一说
And by the way,
恭喜
Congratulations.
你现在是巴尔的摩城市教育委员会 的少数民族承包商了
You are now a minority contractor for the light bulb supply
为其供应电灯泡
To the Board of Education City of Baltimore.
我对灯泡了解个屁
What the fuck I know about light bulbs, man?
你知道B&B的信笺抬头怎么写吧
Do you know how to put the words on a B&B letterhead?
拜托 伙计 放松
Come on, man, relax,
这些事都有白小子们干
White guy's doing all the work.
你只是这笔授权拨款的幌子而已
You're just his beard for the Empowerment grant.
这可是坐在暗处每月五千的额外收入
That's an extra five Gs a month for just laying in the cut.
明白钱怎么来了吗
See how it work?
我会让你发起来的 String
I'm gonna bring you along, String, but
但这不是一夜就能成功的
It ain't gonna be an overnight thing.
我们今年玩转这城市...
We spend this year dealing with the city...
第二年跟州做生意
The next doing business with the state.
等到第三年...
However, year three...
我们就可以冲金了
Then we go for the gold.
跟联邦讨价还价
Then we go federal.
接着我们去见手握水龙头的人
Then we see the man with his hand on the faucet.
- 什么水龙头 - HUD的水龙头  (美国住房和城市发展部)
- What faucet? - The HUD faucet,
钱的水龙头
The money faucet.
听着 伙计
Look, man,
我不知道我们为什么要等三年
I don't know why we got to wait three years for that shit.
我现在就想着冲了
I'm ready to run now.
不 不行
No. You're not.
我是说 无意冒犯
I mean, forgive me but
不过你还是有点街头混混的思想
You still showing a little bit of that street corner mentality.
对花在许可证上的钱锱铢必较
Bugging about every dime you spend about the permits,
在筹备竞选委员会上
About setting up a PAC
在砸钱进行再竞选上都是如此
About dropping cash into re-election war chests...
顺便一说 这也是我的外快来源
Which, by the way, is how I get my gravy.
听着 赚钱是要花钱的 String...
Look, it takes money to make money, String...
否则 随便哪个乞丐都能称王了
Otherwise, hell, every pauper'd be a king.
而我要说的是
And I'm saying
我现在就要干
I'm ready to run now.
三年
Three years.
爬
Crawl,
走
Walk,
最后才是跑
And then run.
- 不 伙计 毛要卷点 - 嗯 嗯
- No, man, nappy up there a little bit more. - Yeah, yeah.
还有眼睛...
And the eyes...
他有双豆大的眼睛
He had little beany eyes.
他妈的什么是豆大的眼睛?
What the fuck is beany eyes?
你知道 小老鼠眼
You know, little rat-eyes.
嗯 好吧 嘿 在那弄颗痣
Yeah, all right. Yo, put a mole on there.
他没痣
He didn't have a mole.
他有
He did, too.
你是被那拿枪指着你脑门的狗日的 吓得尿裤子了
You was just too busy shitting yourself
才没正眼他一眼
With that whistle to your dome to see the motherfucker.
靠 我看了
Shit, fuck I did.
你们怎么知道怎么摆弄这个
How do you know how to do this?
伙计 你怎么会不知道怎么摆弄这个
Man, how you don't know how to do this?
让他耳朵突出点
Make his ears stick up.
- 为什么 - 因为我让你这么做
- Why? - 'Cause I told you to.
靠 好啦
Oh, shit, okay.
给他弄双大眼睛
Give him light eyes.
- 为什么 - 因为我他妈让你这么干
- Why? - 'Cause I fucking told you to.
好 你能让他们靠近吗
Okay, can you make them crossed?
太他妈酷了
This is fucking cool.
来看这些愣头青弄面部成像
Check out these knuckleheads on the Make-A-Face.
把那个移下来点
Bring that down.
嗯 等等
Yeah, hang on.
- 哥们 我告诉你我不是为这个 - 去他妈的
- My brother, I'm telling you that is not what this is all about - Fuck this shit.
听着 我只是想让我的管区适于居住
Look, I'm just trying to make my district livable.
我在几个地方放弃几个街角 但挽救了其他的街角
I write off a few blocks in a few places, but I save the rest.
无意冒犯 但你这像是盲人摸象
No offense, but you're like the blind man and the elephant.
事实比你摸到的要大得多只是你看不见
It's a lot bigger than what you got your hand on you just can't see it.
- 看不见什么 - 一个饱含痛苦之村 而你就是市长
- See what? - A great village of pain and you're the mayor.
饮用水在哪
Where's your drinking water?
厕所在哪
Where's your toilets,
暖气 电?
Your heat, your electricity?
收针头的垃圾车呢...
Where's the needle truck...
分发避孕套呢
The condom distribution,
戒毒治疗呢
The drug treatment intake?
这里一半的人都会挂掉...
Half these people are dying on their feet...
另一半也不得幸免
And the other half's gonna catch what's killing them.
你看  他们并不比之前分散在四周时更糟糕
Look, they ain't no worst off than when they were all over the map.
现在只是聚集到一个地方 如此而已
Now they're just in one place, is all.
而这地方就是地狱
And that place is hell.
你看 我是警察
Look, I'm a police.
所以我能把人关起来 也能把他赶出某个街角
So I can lock a man up or I can move his ass off the corner.
你如果还想让我办得更多
Now, you want anything more than that,
那你找错人了
You're in the wrong shop.
嘿 让她头发更直点
Hey, yo, make her hair a little bit more straight.
- 嗯 - 长一点 要有刘海
- ??? - Make it long. With bangs.
嗯 要的就是这个
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
眼睛中国化一点 像Beyonce
Now Chinese up them eyes, like Beyonc?
颧骨再高点
Get them cheekbones up a little bit.
不 伙计 这太高了
No, man, that's too much.
她现在看着就像个长头发的馅饼烤盘
She's starting to look like a pie tin with hair now, yo.
等等
Hang on.
很好 嘴唇弄丰满点
Yeah, all right. Pillow those lips a little bit.
嗯 就弄成那样
Oh, yeah, hook me up with that.
耶
Yeah.
你手上有这样的牛人吗
Yo, you got one of these does asses?
干嘛
What?
嗯 就是这样
Yeah, that's what's up. Hey.
嘿 两位
Hey, guys.
你好
How you doing?
我们在查一笔买卖
We're looking for a cash purchase in here.
也许是几部Trac电话
Maybe a couple of Trac phones.
约一周前 很可能是黑人
Week or so back. Black guy most likely.
噢 当然 那个人
Oh, sure, that guy.
每两周来一次
Every two weeks for him.
上次 八部手机 差不多900块
Last time, eight phones. Almost $900.
很大一笔Ring Dings 不是吗
That's a lot of Ring Dings, no?
Ring Dings?
一个笑话
A joke.
你有什么交易记录吗
You got some kind of transaction record?
找找总会有的
Seek and you shall find.
等等
Hang on.
927块2毛4
$927.24.
我们能看那天的监控录像吗
Can we have the tape for that day?
没录像 我们每天更新
No tape. I rewind every day.
- 我能保留吗 - 当然
- Keep this? - Sure.
我们他妈的现在怎么办
What the fuck do we do now?
给这家伙买盒录像带?
Buy this guy a box of videotape?
还是在这破地方扎营一周 寄望那小子还走一样路线?
Or camp out in this shithole for a week, hoping our boy runs the same route?
我只知道我要集中精力做点什么 否则又要倒退了
I just know I got to put my mind on something or I'm gonna slide back.
我要控制自己 知道我的意思吗
Need to be in control of myself, you know what I'm saying?
- 为自己的生活做主 - 不错嘛
- Take command of your life. - Something.
培养些自律
Cultivate some self-discipline.
或者别的什么
Or whatever.
如果我告诉你
What if I told you that there's a
有种自由...
Certain liberation...
并非存在于控制或自控中
not in command or in self-control,
- 而是存在于屈服中呢 - 那看你是向谁屈服了
- But in surrendering? - Well, that depends on who you surrendering to.
噢 那个啊...
Oh, that. Hey...
无意冒犯
All due respect,
你那套话可以省省了
You can stow that patter right here and now.
听着 我不觉得我是为了自己这么做
Look, it ain't about me doing for me, I don't think.
可能要比那更多
Might need to be about more than that.
你们带来了本月下降百分之二的犯罪率
So you're bringing in an overall decline of 2 percent for the month...
但如果我看明白了
but if I read this correctly,
这大半归因于西区分局 百分之八的犯罪率下降?
Almost half of that's coming from an eight-percent drop in the Western District?
Colvin警长在他的月度统计中
Major Colvin is himself willing to acknowledge the possibility of a
也愿意承认统计学上偏离的可能性
Statistical variation from the mean in his monthly stats.
偏离 嗯?
Variation, huh?
先生们 如果我细看 西区分局的事件报告...
Gentlemen, if I look through the Western incident reports...
我是可能发现更少的犯罪呢
Am I likely to find less crime,
还是发现更多被降级或未立案的事件?
Or more incidents which have been downgraded or unfounded?
因为这种偏离让我 嗅到一丝篡改的味道...
Because this kind of variation screams manipulation to me...
如果我搞错了
And if I'm wrong about that,
如果这里面确实没有篡改...
If indeed there is no manipulation involved...
我倒想知道Colvin警长...
I would like to know exactly what it is that Major Colvin...
学了什么你其他指挥官学不到的招数
Has learned about police work that eludes the rest of your commanders.
议员 我向您保证 这些数据未经篡改 我们不会那么做
Councilman, I assure you, these stats are not massaged. We don't do that.
我不会那么做
I don't do that.
我也不会让我的人那么做
And I won't allow my people to do that.
我们感觉这确实是一次偏差
Our feeling is that it's genuinely an aberration.
如果下月还是这样...
And if it repeats itself next month...
- 那它就可接受进一步审查 否则... - 那么进行下一项议题
- Then it bears closer examination. Otherwise... - Moving on to new business, then.
我们怎么处理对证人的帮助
How are we fixed for witness assistance?
警局有足够的预算保证有危险的证人...
Does the Department have sufficient funds to ensure pre-trial security...
庭审前的安全吗
For any endangered witnesses?
我们有市里能负担的
We have the resources
足够的资源 我保证
That the city can afford, I'm sure.
我知道你没立场批评市长
I understand you're in no position to criticize the Mayor.
我也不会这么做
Nor would I.
你也不会这么做
Nor would you.
所以请允许我问个问题
So allow me to ask the question.
这城市愿意付出多大代价...
What is this city willing to pay...
让平民能来到法院
To make it possible for ordinary people to come down to the courthouse
履行指证帮派和罪犯的市民义务呢
And perform the civic duty of bearing witness against gangsters and criminals?
多少资源才能与那样的义务相称
What resources are commensurate with that kind of commitment?
你想的话可以继续扮演好士兵
You can play the good soldier if you want, Commissioner...
局长 但我要正式地说
but I want to go on the record here
这个政府一再地推卸责任
In saying that this administration has passed the buck time and again
疏于保护履行义务的市民
And failed to protect those citizens who demonstrate that kind of commitment
把他们的生命和生计置于危险之中
And put their lives and livelihood at risk.
我要说的是我跟我同事一样
I would only like to add that I feel as my colleague does
认为这个政府让我们的社区失望
That this administration has failed this community.
十分糟糕
Miserably.
而我们该做些什么
And we need to do something about this.
来啊
Come on.
嘿
Hey!
你们是朋友
Y'all are friends.
像兄弟一样
You're like brothers.
失去这点 你们就什么都失去了
You lose that, you lose every damn thing.
玩去吧
Go on.
孩子们弄坏了个篮筐
Kids messed up a good hoop.
所以弄了个像桃筐一样的东西
Now they got one looks like the original peach basket
然后就对它爱不释手
And they hanging onto it like a tit.
我也不知道
I don't know.
也许该搞个竞标赛什么的
Maybe I should get up some kind of tournament.
你打篮球吗
You play basketball?
我都不怎么爱好球啊棒啊
Never was much for balls and sticks.
我只用双手的
I was all about my hands.
- 拳击手? - 对
- Boxer? - Yeah.
拳击?
Boxing?
我知道有个有些孩子去的地方
I know a place where some of the kids go but
不过离这可不近
It ain't near close enough to here.
我不介意去看看
I wouldn't mind taking a look at it.
至少有个大概印象
Get a mental picture at least.
嘿 那边在搞什么
Hey, yo, what the hell's going on here?
警察把这里和其他几个地方 的活动都禁止了
Police pushed all the action down here and a couple other places.
执事认为也许会有些人
The deacon thinks that maybe some people should come in here
来接管这里
And take over the situation.
你是那些人吗
Are you that people?
也许算其中之一吧
One of them, maybe.
我叫Roman 伙计
Roman, man.
Dennis
Dennis.
你就在这坐着
You should lay back on this one.
我自己进去跟Buford Pusser谈谈
Let me go talk to Buford Pusser in there alone.
什么
Excuse me?
这告诉人们我了解自己的工作
And what it shows people is that I know my business.
基于事实 我会让人负起责任
That I will hold people accountable based on the facts.
- 这是在做正确的事 - 你又来了
- This is about what's right. - There you go again.
- 什么 - 你觉得政治就是赢一场争论?
- What? - Do you think politics is only about winning the argument?
在正确的时间有正确的事实就能赢?
That whoever has the right fact at the right moment wins?
Clinton有事实
Clinton had facts.
Kennedy有事实 没错 但Reagan呢
Kennedy had facts. Yeah, but Reagan?
如果他的人生靠的是事实 他一个都拿不出
He couldn't have summoned a fact if his life depended on it.
这不仅是事实的事 还在于你如何运用
It's not just facts, it's how you use them.
还有Tommy 当你掌握了一两件事实
And Tommy, when you get hold of a fact or two
你就得理不饶人
You go smart-ass and start beating on people.
- 是 那是... - 克林顿和里根总统...
- Yeah, that's... - Clinton and Reagan...
当他们要说话时...
When they got up to speak...
他们会让屋子里的人舒舒服服的 充满自信
They gave everyone in the room comfort and confidence.
你喜欢那些家伙 你高兴地以为他们也喜欢你
You liked those guys. You were happy to think that they even liked you.
你是说我不讨喜?
You're saying I'm not likable?
Jen?
你在家跟我说话时
When you're at home talking with me
不像在委员会 不像在镜头前  都会表现很好
Not the Council, not the cameras, you're great.
你告诉我什么对你重要时
When you tell me what's really important to you,
我会相信
I believe.
你聪明 有野心
You're smart, and you're ambitious,
你比大部分人牙尖嘴利
And you've got a sharper tongue than most.
你能接待来者 能说好故事...
You can hold court and you can tell a good story...
你想的话可以赢得争论
And you can win the argument if you want.
你参加的那些节目 Tommy
All of that shows, Tommy.
还有在巴尔的摩市委员会会议上 你都表现得很好
And at a Baltimore City Council meeting, it shows well.
但如果你想成为市长
But if you want to be Mayor,
或参议员 甚或有天成为州长
Or Senator, or Governor one day
让他们看到更多特质
Show them something more.
巴尔的摩 嗯?
Baltimore, huh?
我和老婆周年纪念上Harbor去
Went up there to the Harbor with my wife for our anniversary.
两杯啤酒就要了12块
Charged us $12 for two beers.
靠 这算好的了
Shit, that's the least of it.
整个市区在急剧恶化
The whole damn town's going to hell in a handbasket.
猜猜现在谁在唱主角
And guess who's running the show?
谁
Who?
你觉得是谁
Who do you think?
警局 市政府 法院
The Department, City Hall, the courts.
靠 法院?
Shit, the courts?
你知道他们把法官 陪审团和疑犯
You know what they call it when judge, jury
同去搞家庭烤肉称作什么吗
And perp all go to the same family barbecue?
捉放爱 (美国电影)
Catch and release.
不是吧
No shit.
愿上帝宽恕那些上法庭的白人
May God have mercy on any poor white boy going to trial.
就是从那时起 大家都在浮夸地谈论公正
That's when everybody's got their ass in the air talking about justice.
迫不及待要把人都判无期徒刑
Can't wait to throw away the key.
我是说 他们也不是都那么坏
I mean, they're not all so bad.
事实上 有不少好人
Actually, there's a lot of good ones.
要找我的话用无线电
I'm on the radio if you need me.
我老婆
My wife,
Carol-Ann
Carol-Ann.
有些人非常好的
Some very good ones.
你大驾光临 我有什么...
Is there anything specific I can help you with
能帮到你的 警探
While you're down here, Detective?
还是这仅是一次礼节性的拜访?
Or is this just a courtesy call?
你知道 你该见见我搭档 你会喜欢她的
You know, you should meet my partner. You'd like her.
不能正面跟这小子冲突
Can't go through the front on this boy.
所以我想着绕到他身后
So I'm thinking we're gonna have to creep around the back.
让Devonne去办
Get Devonne on it.
这个是解决另一个麻烦用的
I got this for that other problem.
这是谁
Who this?
记得肥脸Rick吧
Remember Fatface Rick, right?
跟String去合作运行会议那个 这是他堂妹 Trina
Been going to them co-op meetings with String. That's his cousin, Trina.
- 哦 你是说有个大屁股的Trina - 对 你去办
- Oh, you mean, Trina with the big old ass. - Yeah, you on it.
这是她办公电话 你知道她现在在哪工作吗
That's her work number. You know where she working at nowadays?
她现在在社会服务部工作
She over at the Department of Social Services.
你觉得Omar会去领钱?
So you think Omar getting a check?
不 现在不会 但我是说 这之前
No, not now. But, I mean, once upon a time before
也有人给过小Omar一把散弹枪不是吗
Some fool gave little Omar Little a shotgun. I mean,
那混蛋总归是谁的孩子 对吧
Cocksucker was somebody's child, right?
所以我想 他们的记录某处
So I'm thinking, somewhere down in them records
总有一两个叫Omar的人
Is one or two names of Omar's people.
懂了吗
You feel me?
你确定想让我们同时对付Marlo和Omar?
You sure you want us on Marlo and Omar both?
我是说 自从我们搞定他的婊子 Omar还没回来找过我们
I mean, Omar ain't come back on us since we got his bitch.
- 所以也许... - 听着 我回来了 Charles
- So maybe... - Look, I'm home, Charles.
我回来了
I'm home.
怎么样
What's up?
生意办得怎么样 String?
Taking care of business, String?
我也是 伙计
Me too, man.
我也是
Me, too.
东区对我们毫无防备?
East Side wasn't ready for us, huh?
那正是我要说的
That's what I'm saying.
对 我熟知BaBa Jani和他的24小时营业店
Yeah, I know all about BaBa Jani and his 24-hour turnover.
也是我一块心病
It's a real pain in my ass, too.
他跟这里学校的孩子有很大纠纷
He's got a real problem with the school kids there.
每天下午3点
Every afternoon come 3:00,
他们把他逼近柜台
They go in there crowd him at the counter,
偷掉所有的汽车和枪械杂志
Boost all the car and gun magazines.
那个监控录像雪花太多了
That surveillance tape's so grainy now
就像是看着暴风雪里的一群水牛
It's like watching a herd of buffalo in a snowstorm.
不过
But
我的保险人 Bob...
My insurance man, Bob...
我让他把摄像头装在这正对BaBa的停车场
I got him to turn this camera here right on BaBa's parking lot.
现在我一有麻烦
Now, anytime I have a real problem,
就找Bob调出他的录像
I just come to Bob and pull his tape.
早上我给你弄份录像
I can get a copy of that for you in the morning.
你的 呃
You, uh...
你的那个搭档
Your partner there.
有点混账
Bit of an asshole.
真的啊?
For real?
嗯
Yeah.
对 右手上来点
Yeah, right hand up.
知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
这是道德闹剧
It's moral midgetry.
弄得世界他妈的天翻地覆
Turn the fucking world upside down
把那些脑残的街头小混混当王子对待
And treat these brain-dead corner yo's like princelings.
你看见现在街角多清净了吗
You see how clean the corners are?
每个区 街道拥堵程度是以前的一半
In every sector, street traffic is half what it was.
去他的 这是错的 这就是不对的
Fuck that. It's wrong, and it's wrong.
好像别的方式就对一样 我们一直做得很好
Like the other way was right because we were doing so well.
Colvin怎么回答的
And Colvin's answer is what?
为毒贩保驾护航? 用现金把他们淹死?
Ride shotgun for hoppers? Drown them in cash money pay?
Colvin? 他一直都是个好警察
Colvin? He's always been good police.
那他就该知道令人伤心的
Then he's got to know what a fucking heartbreaker
就是每天早上醒来
It is to wake up every morning,
- 为这破事穿上制服 - 他也得穿 伙计
- Suit up for this shit. - He's got to suit up too, man.
总得有人跟上面反映一下
Somebody should dime the brass about this shit.
- 或给太阳报 - 我问你
- Or the Sun papers. - Let me ask you something.
这儿有人没遇到麻烦 让Colvin帮你解决的吗
Anybody here ever get jammed up and not have Colvin go to the wall for you?
他在进行一些尝试
The man is trying something.
也许难以忍受 但管用
It may be hard to stomach, but it's working.
服务了30年 你们不觉得 他配得上些施展的空间吗
After 30 years, don't you think he's earned the right to some elbow room on this?
去他的 无论如何已经超过预定时间了
What the fuck. This thing is on borrowed time, anyhow.
当我们决定
And when we do decide
放弃Hamsterdams
To jump on Hamsterdams
他们就会回到以前的街角 对吧
They're just gonna go back to their regular corners, right?
如果我们不管的话
If we ever jump out on it.
我倒不知道我们会不管
I don't know that we're gonna.
而我要说的是 让我们像他一贯挺我们那样挺他
All I'm saying is let's give the guy the same backup he's always given us.
我就想说这个
That's all I'm saying.
我发誓 太阳一出来 我们拿上那该死的录像就走
I swear, as soon as the sun comes up, we grab that damn tape and go.
这地方让我想哭
This place makes me want to cry.
我一半的婚姻生活就是住在这种小房子里
Hey, I spent half my marriage in rooms like this.
你怎么做到的
How could you do it?
什么
What?
不停地骗你前妻
Go nonstop hound on your ex like that.
简单
It's easy.
就告诉她我正在引渡的路上
Just tell her I was on the road working an extradition.
有很多引渡
Lots of extraditions.
我想三年间大概带回来了五百来个亡命者
Brought back something like 500 fugitives in a three-year period, I think.
我说的不是这个
That's not what I meant.
是啊
Right.
你回家了 嗯?
So, you're back in the house, huh?
咽下几口苦水她就让我回去了
Ate some shit and she took me back, yeah.
不过我都不确定我是不是想回去
I ain't sure I even want to be back, though.
引渡?
Extraditions, huh?
Cheryl会看穿的
Cheryl would see right through that shit.
不 很简单的
No, it's easy.
只要关机 让她联系上你搭档
You just keep your cell off, make sure she can reach your partner.
搭档告诉她
Partner tells her,
"Kima在庭上"或者别的什么
"Kima's in court" or whatever.
搭档打给汽车旅馆的你 给你提个醒...
Partner calls you in the motel, gives you the heads up...
你晚点再打回去 "嘿 什么事"
You call her back later like, "Hey, what's up?"
连个装自慰器的小盒都没有
Ain't even got a quarter box for the Magic Fingers.
也许你不需要装那玩意的盒子
Maybe you don't need a quarter box for that.
装什么
For what?
自慰器
Magic fingers.
你了解我的
You know me.
你在骗钱?
You hustling?
在教学
Educating.
收费还是免费
Are you charging for it or tuition-free?
他学到的智慧可是学费的十倍不止
Tuition will come back to him tenfold in acquired wisdom.
再说 世上没什么比"免费"更昂贵的了
Besides, nothing in the world's more expensive than "free."
到此为止了
That's all she wrote.
翻倍吧
Let's double it.
不 伙计 我不想从上教堂的人手上赚钱
No, man, I don't like taking money from a churchgoing man.
- 三倍 - 你开球吧 执事
- Triple it. - Your break, Deacon.
就Hamsterdam我们该再谈谈
We need to talk some more about Hamsterdam.
听着 伙计 我没说过那里情况很好
Look, man, I never said it was pretty.
问题可不是好不好
Pretty doesn't even come close to the problem.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我有个报告会要参加
I've got a COMSTAT meeting.
晚点再来
I'll drop by later on.
- 这么说执照没问题? - 对 这周 目前为止一切正常
- So we good with the permits? - Yeah, this week, so far, so good.
好
All right.
看啊
Look at you.
- 谁 - 胖子Coates
- Who? - Chunky Coates.
- 什么人 - 你不知道胖子?
- Who's that? - You don't know Chunky?
他拥有这个街区
He's got the properties down the block
一直到Paca街一边的房产
And over on the even side of Paca Street.
我第一次见那胖子
When I first met that fat man,
他的办公室小得无法想象
He had an office so small you had to leave the room to change your mind.
接着两年前他开始 跟你伙计Clay Davis做生意
Then two years ago he started running with your man, Clay Davis.
看看现在 你这大肥佬
Look at you now, you big sassy bitch.
好点了?
That better?
嘿 Fitzhugh探员
Hey, Special Agent Fitzhugh,
如果那是你真名的话
if that is in fact your real name.
FBI也来掺一脚了?
FBI in on this?
他们只是看中我的"玩具"而已 Lester打给我 我就送过来了
I am only loved for my toys. Lester called and I delivered.
带子拿到了?
You got the tape?
日期10l10l04 15点4分30秒...
Date of 10l10l04. 15:04 hours, 30 seconds...
收银机纸带上的
by the register tape.
Barksdale老妈?
Mama Barksdale?
D'Angelo的母亲
D'Angelo's mother.
她突然给McNulty打电话询问 她儿子在监狱上吊的事
She cold-called McNulty about her son on the jailhouse hanging.
她因为那捕风捉影的事打给我们?
She's calling us on that weak shit?
Briana吗 对
Is this Briana? Right.
你打来询问你儿子的事 我现在回你的留言
You called about your son. I'm returning that message.
没东西
Nothing there.
太小了 没哪个凡人能...
It's so tiny. No mere mortal can...
看见他刚才干了什么吗
You see what he just did?
什么 他又干了一次
What? He did it again.
他是谁啊 从哪来
Who is this man? Where does he come from?
有人能阻止他吗
Can anybody stop him?
别伤害我们 求你 我的眼睛 我的眼睛
Please don't hurt us, please. My eyes! My eyes!
太大太亮太清晰了
It's so big and clear and bright.
我去趟凶杀科
I'll be at Homicide.
有时你还是会吓着我 知道吗
Sometimes you still scare me, you know that?
在我的世界 你知道 我要达到今时今日的地位...
In my world, do you have any idea what I had to do...
我要付出什么吗
to get where I am today?
当我说我准备好了 你最好相信我
And when I say I'm ready, you best believe it.
通过有效利用警力资源
Through the effective use of resources,
增加警员出勤...
and increased police presence...
和跟社区的紧密交流...
and an intensive reach-out into the community...
我们得以对这些地区产生显著影响...
we've been able to have a significant impact on these areas...
总的来说 犯罪率下降了十二个百分点
to the effect of a 12-percent decrease overall.
十二个百分点
Twelve percent.
累积的
Cumulatively.
四周以来的数据
Over four weeks.
警长 我知道几周前 你说数据有大的下降时...
Major, I know I gave you shit when your stats took a jump...
我没在意...
a few weeks back...
但你现在要把这数据硬塞给我吗
but now you're gonna shove the numbers right up my ass?
你有点易怒啊 不是吗
It's kind of pouty of you, isn't it?
十二个百分点
Twelve percent.
我之前没弄虚作假 现在也没有
I didn't cook them then, I ain't cooking them now.
说真的 Bunny
Seriously, Bunny,
市委员会已经发问了...
I already got the City Council asking questions...
问上周你报告的八个百分点是怎么回事
about the eight-percent drop you posted last week.
我们只是想取悦市长 并不想因此坐牢
We just want to please the Mayor, not go to jail behind this shit.
你知道 有时上帝真的在听 长官
You know, sometimes the gods do listen, sir.
在西区不会 Daniels队长?
Not in the Western, they don't. Lieutenant Daniels?
- 长官? - 你是不是这件事儿的功臣啊
Sir? You want to take credit for any of this?
你的小队在那区干了几周了
Your unit's been working in that district a couple of weeks.
我们还没什么收获
We're barely up on anything.
事实上 我们在查的组织还在争斗 还在抛尸
In fact, the crews we're looking at are still beefing, still dropping bodies.
太棒了
Amazing.
犯罪下降了 却没人愿意领功
Crime is down and no one wants to take any credit.
这算是什么情况啊
What is wrong with this picture?
如果我计划提取你所有的报告编号 进行调查你不介意吧
You don't mind if I have Planning and Research pull all your CC numbers.
确保不是1和2之间的小数点搞错了
Make sure there's not a decimal point missing between the one and the two?
尽管调查 副局长 数据不会变
Pull everything, Deputy. That number will stand.
我打电话是因为我听说你去拜访了Donette
I called because I heard you went and visited Donette.
你告诉她 我儿子的死不是自杀 对吗
Told her my son's death couldn't have been no suicide.Is that right?
没错
I did do that.
D'Angelo是上吊自杀的
D'Angelo hung himself.
用的不是他们发现绕在他脖子上的皮带
Not with the belt they found around his neck.
不是在门把和地板之间
Not at that distance between the doorknob and the floor.
那你什么意思
So what are you saying?
我什么意思?
What am I saying?
不
No.
没人有这胆子
Nobody would've dared.
我哥哥 他舅舅 他会...
My brother, his uncle, would have...
我同意
I agree with you.
没人有这胆子
Nobody would've dared.
除了...
Unless...
Avon和D是一家人
Avon and D was family.
家人 是啊
Family, right.
这只是你一面之词 对吧
This is just you talking, right?
我是说 还有别人这么说吗
I mean, anyone else saying it?
没 只有我
No, just me.
没别人在乎
No one else cares.
是啊
Right.
只是 我不确定 在里面...
It's just, I don't know, on the inside...
如果某人跟你有仇要对付你 他们会用自制小刀
if somebody's going after you, has got a beef, sees red, they use a shank.
很快就结束
It's quick and it's over.
D'Angelo是被勒死的
D'Angelo was strangled,
这是有计划的
which is planned.
你需要等待时机  需要找到他独自一人的时候
You need the time, you need the isolation.
听着 很抱歉 这一团乱麻是我引起的...
Look, I'm just sorry I brought this whole mess up to begin with...
因为说实话 反正没人会为此做什么
'cause frankly, no one's gonna do shit about it anyhow.
杀了他的人想伪装成自杀...
Whoever killed him wanted to pass it off as a suicide...
警察也很高兴少调查一件谋杀案
and the cops are happy enough to have one less murder to investigate.
最重要的是 Anne Arundel的检察官才不在乎
On top of that, the Anne Arundel State's Attorney doesn't give a fuck.
我本来也不该在乎 所以...
I'm not supposed to give a fuck, so...
我猜你儿子不过是正好被夹在中间了
I guess your son just got squeezed between the sides.
夹在什么中间
Squeezed between what sides?
听着 两年前...
Look, two years ago...
我们监听你哥哥的组织的电话 比电话公司的还多...
we hung more wire on your brother's crew than AT&T...
而最终 D'Angelo差点 就要供出所有人 所有事了
and at the end, D'Angelo was this close to flipping giving up everybody, everything.
但你也知道 对吧
But you know all that, right?
是你去了拘留中心...
You were the one who went down to that detention center...
劝你儿子别犯傻
and talked your son out of a deal.
我还有点喜欢你儿子 知道吗
I kind of liked your son, you know?
总的来说 他是个还算正派的孩子
All things considered, he was a pretty decent kid.
没人替他仗义执言让我很不好受
And it grinds me that no one ever spoke up for him.
而且我看以后也不会有
Seems to me that nobody ever will.
不过 总的来说 抱歉我打扰了你儿媳...
But, mostly at this point, I'm sorry I bothered his girl...
抱歉她又打扰了你
and I'm sorry she bothered you.
为什么去找她
Why go to her?
为什么不先来找我
Why not come to me first?
说实话吗
Honestly?
我是要找真正关心这孩子的人
I was looking for somebody who cared about the kid.
我的意思是 我也说了
I mean, like I said,
是你让他去服刑的 对吧
you were the one who made him take the years, right?
红色头子呼叫红孩儿
Red leader to red boys.
红二号回话
Red two come in.
起司牛肉三明治很难吃 混蛋
Cheese steak has a problem, bitch.
给我留些薯条
Save me some fries, yo.
想吃薯条? 带点现钱来吧
You want fries? I suggest you bring some cash up here.
你相信吗
Can you believe this?
没有打手 一切光明正大的
No muscle, it's all out in the open.
不 不 不 伙计 这一切
No, no, no, man. This right here, boy.
好得有点不真实啦
This too good.
嘿 这像是某种大套 来逮犯罪大师的
Hey, yo, this some kind of full-tilt setup, man to catch a master scoundrel.
Capone或者别的什么人(美国帮派分子)
Capone and whatnot.
小子 他们可能 在每个排屋窗子后面都藏了警察
Boy, they probably got police behind every one of them row house windows.
打劫这里? 一定会阴沟翻船的
Hit this? You must be tripping.
回吧 James
Home, James.
我告诉你 小子 脑子要融入游戏...
I'm gonna tell you, boy, you better keep your head back in the game...
否则你会害咱俩被逮住
or you gonna land us both in the pokey.
你看什么
What you looking at?
你啊
You.
是吗
Yeah?
我喜欢你的眼睛 像猫一样
I like your eyes. They're like cat eyes.
你跟谁来的
Who you here with?
她们
Them.
就这样啊
That's it?
什么猫
What kind of cat?
什么
What?
我的眼睛像什么猫
What kind of cat are my eyes like?
大猫咪
A big cat.
你跟她们来的 没其他人了?
You here with them and no one else?
我说过了
I said that.
想跳舞吗
You want to dance?
靠 不想
Hell, no.
想喝一杯吗
You want a drink?
不 也不想
No, I don't do that neither.
那你想干什么
What do you do?
Gene 这个我跟你说起过吗
Gene, this spot I'm telling you about?
我们说的是肺结核 艾滋病 梅毒...
We're talking TB, HIV, syphilis...
疱疹 虱子
herpes, lice.
就像个五英亩的培养皿
It's like a five-acre petri dish.
在那里面...
You get in there now...
想运营什么卫生计划和社会计划都成
you can run every health program or social program you want.
任何自由主义工程都离不开时代局限性
Hell, every kind of liberal-ass project never got off the page it was written on.
侏罗纪公园
Jurassic Park.
这么说 你是说这是个 获批准的露天毒品交易市场?
So, you're saying that this is a sanctioned open-air drug market.
不 没有官方批准 该说是被默许的
No, it's not officially sanctioned. It's more like it's tolerated.
正因此我找上你们和公共卫生学校...
That's why we came to you and the Public Health School...
而不是市卫生局
not the City Health Department.
针头交换处 药品服务 避孕套 艾滋检测
Needle exchange, drug outreach, condoms, HIV testing.
在同一个地方你再找不到更多人了
Y'all ain't never gonna reach more people in the same spot.
这么说如果市里不知道这地方 这就...
So if the city doesn't know about it then that makes it...
复杂了
Complicated.
那意味着临时的
That means temporary.
走了就没了 老大
You move it or you lose it, boss.
挺爽啊
That was nice.
很受用
It worked for me.
明天有空吗
You free tomorrow?
明天?
Tomorrow?
你可以去我家 除了我奶奶没别人
You could come back to my crib. Nobody's there but my grandma.
找张真正的床 慢慢爽
Get us a real bed. Take some time with it.
你号码
Give me your number.
我说明天 不是催你...
The reason I'm saying tomorrow, not to push...
但后天我就要去佛罗里达的姨妈家了
but day after that I got to go visit my aunt in Florida.
我们明天狂欢一把...
We hook up tomorrow...
长途巴士上我就能慢慢品味了
I got something real nice to think about on that long-ass bus ride.
你先下
After you.
你叫什么来着
What was it again?
Devonne
Devonne.
出租
这家伙每五天都沿相同路线行动
This guy's running his route every five days.
买了很多的一次性手机
That's a shitload of burners.
搞不懂
I don't get it.
他们如此小心的奔走三个州买手机...
They were so careful spreading out the purchases up and down the three states...
照常理他们租车行也该常更换才对
you'd think they'd also switch up rental agencies.
也许那家伙觉得对不起我们
Maybe the guy felt bad for us.
你有复印件吧
You got a copier, right?
巴尔的摩市社会服务局
靠 美女 怎么你瘦了
Damn, girl, what, you lose some weight?
你说什么
Excuse me?
夸你呢
It's just a compliment.
那是Omar夫人?
Yo, that's Mrs. Omar?
对 他奶奶
Yeah, his grandmoms.
那怎么办 把她抓来逼供?
So what, we jack her and make her talk?
笨 她很可能不知道他在哪
Fool, she probably got no clue where he lay his head.
不是吧 伙计 我们就坐在这等 对吧
No, man, we sit and we wait, right?
等什么
Man, wait on what?
蠢货
Stupid motherfucker.
你看 我们上楼会吓着他
Now, see, if we go upstairs, we'll spook him.
所以等他下来 好吗
So he's coming down. All right?
Russell Bell
Russell Bell.
我对B&B很了解 就像我了解其他好多公司一样...
I know B&B like I know a thousand other outfits...
但我不认识他 为什么要和他谈
but I don't know him. Why should I talk to him?
因为Russell是个好人 他要开始挣大钱了
Because Russell's a good man. And he's ready to run.
那就让他跟着你挣大钱吧
Then let him run for you.
等等
Hang on.
等等 搭档
Wait a minute, partner.
你不知道你在跟谁说话
I don't think you know who you're dealing with here.
你知道他是谁吗
You know who that is?
跑鞋穿好了吧 搞定了
Got your running shoes on? You're in.
那就是水龙头?
That's the faucet?
靠 就联邦资金而言 他就是一切
Shit, as far as the federal money's concerned, he's everything.
水龙头 鹅
The faucet, the goose.
- 什么鹅 - 下金蛋的鹅
- What goose? - The one that lays them golden eggs.
这儿不是麦迪逊花园广场 (纽约尼克斯主场)
Madison Square Garden it ain't.
但也能用
But it could work.
你需要人帮你做些清理
You're gonna need a little help with the cleanup.
我会弄好的
I'll piece that together.
这是我的旅途 老兄
This my trip, man.
凡事都要亲力亲为
Need to go from A to B all by myself.
我是可能发现更少的犯罪呢
Am I likely to find less crime,
还是发现更多被降级或未立案的事件?
or more incidents that have been downgraded or unfounded?
因为这种偏离让我 嗅到一丝篡改的味道...
Because this kind of variation screams manipulation to me...
放低语速
Slow your words.
说话时尽量看着对方
Try to lock your eyes on whoever you talk to.
让他们觉得你把他们当回事
Make them think they matter.
用开放 温暖的词 别太尖锐 别太狠
Use open, warm phrases. Nothing sharp, nothing that bites.
那还有什么意思
Where's the fun in that?
你还想我们帮你吗
Do you want this?
这城市愿意付出多大代价让平民...
What is this city willing to pay to make it possible for ordinary people...
- 是我 - 嘿 你好 猫眼?
- It's me. - Hey. How you, Cat Eyes?
你说你几时走来着
Yeah, when you say you leaving again?
明天 今晚一块儿吗
Tomorrow.Wanna get together tonight?
嗯 我们今晚见面
Yeah, we could hook up tonight.
来我家怎么样
How about coming over to my crib?
不 不去你家
No, not your crib.
那去哪
Where then?
去汽车旅馆
Go to a motel.
让我去见你? 哪家
You want me to meet you? Which one?
不知道哪家 见了面再说
I don't know which one. I'll tell you when I see you.
我想尽快见到你
I'd like to see you soon.
行 你知道Lake Trout吗
All right, you know Lake Trout?
外卖店? 在哪
Carry-out? Where?
- 在Woodland - Reisterstown路那边?
- On Woodland. - Off Reisterstown Road?
- 就是那家 - 中午晚些时候?
- That one. - Later this afternoon?
我过去 什么时候见
I'll be there. What time you want to meet?
5点那样
Like 5:00.
5点就是5点 我不说大概时间 5点一过我就走
And 5:00 mean 5:00. I don't truck CP Time. 5:00 and change, I'm gone.
我不会迟到的
I ain't gonna be late.
那好
All right, then.
到时见
See you then.
你怎么看
What you think about that?
我不知道
I don't know.
搞不好刚办事儿就有状况
Might be walking into something a little later.
所以我要你去那踩踩点
So I'm gonna need for you to go up there and get me a read up front.
我哥哥在哪
Where's my brother?
关门 伙计
Shut the door, man.
我们现在在战斗 姐姐 他忙着呢
Yo, we at war right now, sis. So he on that.
我要见他
I need to get with him.
他没带电话
Well, he ain't on the cell phone.
我见到他会让他联系你的 好吗
Soon as I speak to him, I'll get him to you, all right?
难以置信
I can't believe this shit.
有个警察
Heard from this cop.
说D是被谋杀的
He's saying D was murdered.
肯定是McNulty
Oh, that'd be McNulty.
你怎么知道的
How you know?
Levy知道他没办法说服你不去会面...
Well, Levy figured he couldn't talk you out of the meet...
但我真希望他试过了
but I sure wish he tried.
我要见我哥哥
I need to get with my brother.
拜托
Oh, come on.
这个烂警察
This fucking cop.
他想挑拨我们 你看不出来吗
He trying to drive a wedge up in here, man. You can't see it?
听着 我能想象一个母亲...
Look, I can imagine how hard it is for a mother...
要接受这些有多困难
to have to deal with some shit like that. No doubt.
但事实是这些地方欺压黑人
But the fact is these places, they press on niggas.
他只是找到了个提早解脱的方法
He just figured a way to get out of there early.
大家都无能为力
Ain't nothing nobody can do about that.
我是说 你怎么能阻止一个人自杀呢
I mean, how do you protect a man from himself?
Avon在哪 我要去找他
Where Avon at? I'll go to him.
我说过了 我们现在在争夺街角
I told you. We beefing for corners right now.
我一见到他就让他联系你 我保证
As soon as I speak to him, I'll get him to you, I promise.
一个警察不该让一个母亲陷入这种痛苦
A cop shouldn't mess with a mother's pain like that.
任何人都不该
No one should.
给我四个鳟鱼三明治 一个加蛋黄酱...
Yeah, let me get four trout on white, extra mayo on one...
两个加辣酱 一个加番茄酱
hot sauce on two and the other with ketchup.
还要四瓶橙味汽水
And four orange sodas.
那个大屁股黑鬼要了 四个三明治和四瓶汽水
This clown-ass nigga went and got four sandwiches and four sodas, man.
听到了吗
You heard me?
好
Cool.
那些家伙几分钟之内不走 就有点苗头了
Niggas don't roll out in a few minutes, we onto something.
一换一
Drop one, get one!
不 宝贝 这个我有感情了
No, baby, this one's sentimental.
给 这是漂白剂
Here, it's bleach.
把你的产品泡泡就好了
Soak your works and you're good to go.
一换一
Drop one, get one.
让其他女生过来一趟
Get the other girls to come by.
等等
Wait.
帮我发了吧 好吗
Just pass these out for me, okay?
嘿 我只有花生酱了 你有些别的吗
Yo, I just rolled for peanut butter. You got anything else?
- 你看我他妈像谁 Chef Boyardee? - 谁 (美国罐头食品品牌 一个头像)
- The fuck I look like to you, Chef Boyardee? - Who?
等这些狗屎完蛋 我会把你...
Hey, when all this bullshit falls apart, I'm gonna kick your fuck...
慢慢接近他们
Go by them slow.
该死
Oh, shit!
天啊
Oh, my God!
你中枪了?
You hit?
没有
No.
开车 混球 离开这
Drive, motherfucker, get out of here!
你的人最好跟他们吹得一样好
Now your man better be as good as his word.
或是跟你说的那样也成
Or your word.
如果你还有这种心态...
If you are still in possession of that kind of mentality...
那你绝对还没准备好
then you are definitely not ready.
- String... - 等会
- String... - Not now.
- 是Avon - 关门
- It's Avon. - Shut the door.
我们动手吧
Let's do it.
保持联系 搭档
I'll be in touch, partner.
- 什么事 伙计 - Avon中枪了
- What is it, man? - Avon's been hit.
- 哪儿 - 肩膀
- Where? - In the shoulder.
Tater被杀 Avon还活着 伙计
Tater got killed. Avon still breathing, man.
但Briana老缠着我 给我打电话 我得告诉她
But Briana all over me, calling me, man. I need to tell her.
- 不 去他的Briana - 什么
- No, fuck Briana. - What?
让那贱货离我远点 懂了吗
Just keep the bitch away from me, you hear me?
如果你缝牛皮似地给我缝 下一个受伤的就是你了
If you put them pit bull-style stitches in me, the next patient's gonna be you.
- 他认真的 - 怎么 你不喜欢牛皮?
For real. What, you don't like rawhide?
Marlo
Marlo!
终于有点旧时光的感觉了 宝贝
We finna get back to old times, baby.
嘿 Anthony 去哪儿啊
Hey, Anthony. Where you at?
North Mount 1034号 一楼 长官
First floor, 1034 North Mount, sir.
很好
Good.
他们希望我们疯狂反击
They're expecting us to hit back wild.
他们正等着呢 而我们则伺机而动
That's what they're just waiting for, and we're gonna sit back on it for a while.
让他们战战兢兢的
Let them sweat on it.
嘿 我们得谈谈
Yo, we got to talk.
等等
Hold on.
我的意思是 他们总得从街角出来 他们要以此赚钱的 对吧
I mean, he got to come out on his corners, that's how he make money, right?
我们就比比谁的军费更多
We gonna see who got the bigger war chest.
Avon?
开战 嗯?
Straight to the mattresses, huh?
随便啦 什么事 伙计
Whatever. What you want, man?
"战争" 伙计 我们说了不要战争的
"War", man, we past this bullshit.
对 我忘了
Yeah, I forgot.
知道吗 我就觉得我忘了什么 我们是王牌兄弟
You know, I knew I forgot something. We the Trump brothers.
伙计 你不放弃战争...
Man, you don't give this shit up...
我们建立的一切都会付之一炬
you're gonna turn everything we built to shit.
不
No.
是笨蛋兄弟
The Chump brothers.
你知道我和你的区别吗
You know what the difference is between me and you?
我流出来的血是红的 你流出来的是绿的
I bleed red, you bleed green.
你一直以来为我们建立的是什么
What you been building for us?
知道吗 这些天我看着你 我看到了什么
You know what, I look at you these days, you know what I see?
我看见了一个没有国家的人
I see a man without a country.
不够强硬
Not hard enough for this, right here.
也许 只是也许...
And maybe, just maybe...
也不够聪明
not smart enough for them out there.
不够强硬?
Not hard enough?
无意冒犯 但我从没觉得你强硬过
No offense, but I don't think you ever really were.
你有手段 毫无疑问 但...
You got skills, yeah, no doubt, but...
什么
What?
怎么 因为我不会不加选择地 让人脑袋开花 我就不够强硬了?
What, 'cause I don't shoot up a block, indiscriminate, I ain't hard enough?
因为我夺去别人性命前会三思 我就办不成事了?
Because I think before I snatch a life, I ain't into this bullshit?
夺人性命?
Snatch a life?
你夺过谁的命
What life you snatch, huh?
你知道吗 Briana去了市里 见了那个警探
You know, Briana went downtown, man, saw that detective.
那家伙把她脑子里塞满了 D'Angelo不是自杀的想法
Man stoking her head saying that D'Angelo's death was no suicide.
所以呢
Yeah, so?
他没说错
Man ain't wrong about that.
什么
What?
对
Yeah.
我知道你下不了手...
I knew you couldn't do it...
Briana也不会干
and Briana wouldn't do that shit.
但他一定要死 Avon
But there go a life that had to be snatched, Avon.
我把那担子从你肩上卸下挑到我身上...
Yo, man, I took that shit off you, and put it on me, man...
因为那混蛋撑不住了
because that motherfucker was out of pocket with that shit!
他妈的有二十年牢要坐
Twenty years above his fucking head.
他一招 伙计 你我和他妈的Briana都得玩完
He flip, man, they got you and me and fucking Briana!
没门 老兄 绝对不行
No fucking way, man. Hell no!
我知道你们是一家人 你爱他
Now, I know you're family. You loved that nigga.
但你要想说那些"血浓于水"的屁话...
But you want to talk that "blood is thicker than water" bullshit...
到别处说去 黑鬼
take that shit somewhere else, nigga!
那混球会把我们建立的事业都拖垮 杀手!
That motherfucker would have taken down the whole fucking show starting with you, killer!
他会把每个人每件事都搞砸
He was fucking everything and everybody!
让我起来
Let me up.
靠
Oh, shit.